where are my power lifters at because
this video today is for you the rep
Fitness power bar it's fully stainless
steel and it has a tensile strength
rating of 200 000 PSI making it a more
durable longer lasting barbell
man there's a lot to like here let's get
going
[Music]
what's up my people it's Jake back in
the barbing garage gym and in full
review today I've got the rep Fitness
power bar in this video I'm gonna take
you through all the details of this bar
the price the pros and the cons and of
course who should and who should not buy
this barbell but as always before we get
started
gotta let you know we have reviewed a
bunch of barbells on barbin.com to find
more about our best picks just Google
barbant best barbells and find out for
yourself which ones we like the best
okay so some of you may know this but I
gotta clear the air really fast
powerlifting revolves around the big
three movements squat bench and deadlift
and since you do need a barbell to
perform each of these lifts it's good to
have one that's going to pair with them
so in the beginning you know it really
doesn't matter what kind of barbell you
have just as long as it is a solid one
but as you start to get stronger you
start adding on heavier weight for your
lifts the type of bar you have can make
a pretty big difference so power lifting
bars like this one you see here they're
gonna have a deeper knurling that
provides a better grip for those heavier
loads Power Bars also have a higher
tensile strength rating which can handle
those heavy loads we can dive more into
specialty bars and whip on bars for the
big three but for now just know that
power lifting bars have an emphasis on
the knurling and the tensile strength
rating
so what do I like about the rep Fitness
power bar well for starters from end to
end it's fully stainless steel which is
really all you could ever ask for in
terms of protection from rust and
corrosion the knurling you're going to
find here is awesome it's going to make
you feel as if you're freaking glue on
your hands during your lips and you can
add up to 1500 pounds on this bar while
it also has a tensile strength rating of
200 000 PSI meaning it's going to handle
all types of punishment that comes its
way in the gym so as always with the
pros come the cons and with this barbell
the knurling you're going to find here
rep Fitness claims it's on the medium
side but I don't really know if that's
an accurate description since this is a
power bar the knurling is deeper than
one on a more versatile bar and it's
gonna tear up your hands a little bit if
you're wanting to perform those Olympic
style and Crossfit style lifts this is
not the bar to handle those I would
definitely suggest looking at a
different option such as the rep saber
or maybe even the Rogue Ohio bar and
since the sleeves are smooth you have a
higher chance of your weight sliding
around while lifting so you might need
to add in a weight collar to lock those
into place
so listed around 400 on the rep Fitness
website this is a little bit on the
expensive side compared to some other
competition but once you consider the
quality you're finding here it's a
pretty good deal the stainless steel
sleeves are included well some other
companies may make you pay extra for
that extra protection and shipping is
free which is pretty rare when it comes
to fitness equipment if you don't want
to spend 400 at once though rep Fitness
does allow you to split your purchase up
into four interest-free payments of
around 100 bucks this is a pretty good
deal once you consider the stainless
steel the tensile strength and how much
weight you can load onto this barbell
[Music]
okay so let's talk about the build now
with the rep Fitness power bar as I
mentioned this is a fully stainless
steel power bar which is everything you
could hope and dream for in terms of
protection from rust and corrosion
especially if you live in a human
environment the sleeves do have bushings
that are going to allow them to spin but
they're not going to spin as freely as a
more versatile bar so if you're looking
to do those CrossFit and Olympic style
lifts such as a power clean this isn't
the bar for you and the sleeves also
have about 17 inches of loading space
for you to put your plates on and the
diameter of this bar is about 29
millimeters which will really help you
get that good grip you're looking for
and since you can load up to 1500 pounds
and this has a tinsel strength rating of
200 000 PSI this barbell is an absolute
beast in the gym
okay so let's go into more detail now on
the features with the rep Fitness power
bar as I mentioned this is fully
stainless steel make sure you remember
that I want you guys to remember that
the knurling you're going to find here
is listed on the medium side I think
that's in terms of power lifting bars
because if you were to pick up you know
one of those more versatile barbells I
spoke of earlier you're going to tell a
difference between the grip on this one
and one of those you do have a center
knurling on this barbell which is great
for those back squats or anything
utilizing a suitcase grip you'll notice
you only have one neural marking here
well that's because this is not meant
for those Olympic style lifts those type
of barbells are going to have that
outside marking letting you know what
your furthest possible grip can be and
the sleeves on this barbell are as
smooth as butter so your plates have a
really good chance of sliding around so
I would suggest adding in a weight
collar to lock those plates into place
all right y'all I'm gonna walk you
through this barbell now as you can see
it does have that Center knurling which
is awesome in terms of your back squats
it's going to allow that barbell to stay
in place a little bit better sticking
with the knurling it's a little bit on
the medium side in terms of power
lifting bars it's not too abrasive but
you definitely don't want to do any
power cleans with this bar because it's
going to tear up your hands as you can
see sticking with the knurling here
there's only one set of knurling marks a
lot of times you'll notice on barbells
they have double neural markings that's
a barbell that's meant for power cleans
like I said this bar is not for that so
you only have the one which allows you
to get that widest grip possible for
your bench press
now let's talk about the sleeves they do
spin a little bit because of having
bushings in them but they're not going
to spin as freely as a more versatile
bar that's because this bar isn't as
versatile and it's meant for power
lifting only and the sleeves are also
smooth like butter meaning you're going
to need a pair of weight collars to keep
those weight plates locked in place
okay so who should purchase the rep
Fitness power bar well any power lifter
out there that's looking for a bar
that's built to last you're gonna love
this is made from stainless steel it's
going to fight off rust and corrosion at
the highest rate possible and since you
can load up to 1500 pounds and it has a
tensile strength rating of 200 000 PSI
this bar is really going to take any
punishment that comes its way and it
might be the last power bar you ever
need to buy
now what about those people who don't
need to buy this barbell well let's
start with the beginners most likely
while you're beginning weightlifting
you're not really loading on a ton of
weight to your barbell if that's the
case I wouldn't recommend this bar for
you because that's what it's meant for
and if you want a bar that's more
versatile it's going to allow you to do
those power cleans any Olympic style or
CrossFit style lift I'd suggest a
different bar maybe the rep Fitness
saber or the Rogue Ohio bar like I spoke
about earlier those are two really good
options when it comes to those style of
lifts and you know 400 is kind of a lot
of money for a barbell especially once
you consider getting yourself a set of
weight plates If This falls out of your
price range I'd recommend a cheaper bar
but since it's cheaper it's not
guaranteed it's made of stainless steel
like this bar is or guaranteed to even
handle the amount of punishment the rep
Fitness power bar can
well that's all I have for you guys
today on the rep Fitness power bar this
is honestly an awesome barbell for your
power lifting needs and I would
absolutely recommend it for any power
lifter out there watching today before
you crossfitters at home I would avoid
this barbell unless you're just dying to
get your hands torn to shreds by the
knurling because you can load up to 1500
pounds and it has a tensile strength
rating of 200 000 PSI it's gonna handle
everything you throw at it in the gym
and the cherry on top I've said it once
I've said it twice I'm going to say it
again it's fully stainless steel y'all I
don't know what more you could ask for
in a power bar
thanks for watching everybody I hope
this video gave you some more insight on
what this bad boy has to offer you in
the weight room as always stay tuned for
my next video and in the meantime Google
barbin rep Fitness power bar review my
article is going to pull up for you and
you can read everything we discussed
here today I'll catch y'all next time
[Music]
thank you